<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog | Seth Doty</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 15:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examining Organizational Cybersecurity User Experience.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/examining-organizational-cybersecurity-user-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/examining-organizational-cybersecurity-user-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In “Things that make us Smart: Defending Human Attributes in the Age of the Machine” (Norman, 1993), renowned usability expert Don Norman examines the interactions between humans and technology. He argues that technology needs to focus on developing models that fit the minds of humans and not try to focus on designs that force us to conform to the machine’s ideals. This book was written nearly thirty years ago, but its issues still apply today. This paper will examine this issue within the scope of modern business, identifying common issues faced by users. It will then explore how security professionals can affect the secure user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;identify-the-problem&#34;&gt;Identify The Problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pandemic did not just change the working conditions for users and how they interact with an organization, it also changed how malicious groups interact with end users. Within a short time, malicious actors changed tactics to take advantage of the pandemic before organizations could adapt to these new changes (Crossland &amp;amp; Ertan, 2021). This change in malicious tactics began to highlight areas from previous studies around remote work that many organizations may not have properly prepared for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until the pandemic, it was acceptable to blame the end user because it “falls into the category of acceptable accident causes” (Hollnagel, 1983). The quick shift towards remote work and the primary example of issues can be found in papers such as “Reigning in the Remote Employee: Applying Social Learning Theory to Explain Information Security Policy Compliance Attitudes” where it was stated “Remote working has been shown to impact an employee’s intended behaviour concerning cyber security policy, with remote working colleagues having an altered perception or security and privacy policy awareness, as well as lower intentions and ability to comply with information security” (Johnston et al., 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of these issues were previously known to cybersecurity professionals. However, the cybersecurity industry was implementing controls based on flawed data. This risk and the resulting malicious focus were not,” detected via standard survey questions used by information security surveys (which ask about security behaviour alone) - but only when put in the context of other organizational goals. Taken together with the results from the qualitative studies this highlights that most of the studies in this review - which focus on security behaviour alone - may produce results that will not apply in real-world circumstances because their “tunnel vision” on security ignores the other factors driving security behaviour (Karlsson et al., 2017)”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;solutions&#34;&gt;Solutions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As users began to move remotely, cybersecurity policies adapted in a way that was not congruent with the common idea of “trust but verify” used in the industry. Users already considered navigating cybersecurity information “as ‘intimidating’ and ‘overwhelming’ leading to practices of avoidance” (Slupska et al., 2021)”. Cybersecurity policies, and thus the methods to enforce them did not always remember that “goals, values and norms drive behaviour of non-security experts. These studies show that security is ultimately a social construct and as such needs to be negotiated between the different stakeholders in the ecosystem. The benefits of a collaborative stance are also suggested by economics: the time and effort individuals and organizations can expend is a limited resource - and economics tells us that we ignore such constraints at peril to our security goals” (Heath et al., 2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The starting place for ensuring that cybersecurity goals can be achieved is for “Security leadership colleagues should ensure employees at all levels understand the purpose of cyber security controls and the justification for using them, no matter whether they are in their homes or in an office environment, leveraging executive leadership support where this is required” (Crossland &amp;amp; Ertan, 2021). Instead of treating users as the weakest link, they instead need to “demonstrate that creating a sense of procedural fairness regarding rules and regulations is the key to effective information security management. In sum, it is important that, far from presuming that they are the ‘weakest link,’ our end users be dealt with fairly and with trust (Saltzer &amp;amp; Schroeder, 1975).”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the methods of work change and user interaction with technology adapt to new practices, software, and ideas cybersecurity professionals should refer to the 1975 foundational paper The Protection of Information in Computer Systems (Saltzer &amp;amp; Schroeder, 1975) in which one of the key principles stated that human factors and economics (that each user, and the organization as a whole, should have to deal with as few distinct security mechanisms as possible). If the various layers of socio-technical interactions do not begin to focus on this core tenant, we will continue to face a situation where we are forcing compliance with the machine, instead of building a machine that works best for our users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crossland, G., &amp;amp; Ertan, A. (2021). Remote Working and (In)Security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heath, C. P. R., Hall, P. A., &amp;amp; Coles-Kemp, L. (2018). Holding on to dissensus: Participatory interactions in security design. Strategic Design Research Journal, 11(2). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4013/sdrj.2018.112.03&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4013/sdrj.2018.112.03&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hollnagel, E. (1983). Human Error NATO Conference on Human Error, Bellagio, Italy. &lt;a href=&#34;https://erikhollnagel.com/onewebmedia/URTEXT%20on%20HE.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://erikhollnagel.com/onewebmedia/URTEXT%20on%20HE.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Johnston, A., Wech, B., Jack, E., &amp;amp; Beavers, M. (2010). Reigning in the Remote Employee: Applying Social Learning Theory to Explain Information Security Policy Compliance Attitudes (Vol. 3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karlsson, F. J., Karlsson, M., &amp;amp; Åström, J. (2017). Measuring employees&amp;rsquo; compliance - the importance of value pluralism. Inf. Comput. Secur., 25, 279-299.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Norman, D. (1993). Things that make us smart: defending human attributes in the age of the machine. . Diversion Books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saltzer, J., &amp;amp; Schroeder, M. D. (1975). The Protection of Information in Computer Systems. Proc. IEEE, 63, 1278–1308. &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/Saltzer/www/publications/protection/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://web.mit.edu/Saltzer/www/publications/protection/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slupska, J., Dawson Duckworth, S. D., Ma, L., &amp;amp; Neff, G. (2021). Participatory Threat Modelling Extended Abstracts of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems,&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things that make us Smart Book Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/things-that-make-us-smart-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/things-that-make-us-smart-book-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Don Norman’s career has been primarily focused on how humans understand the world around them. His career has given him the opportunity to influence modern computing in multiple ways, whether it was his time as a Vice President of User Experience at Apple Computers, a Benjamin Franklin medal in Computer and Cognitive Science, or his many lectures to students and organizations around the world. This prestige is what led to him being named “One of the World’s Most Influential Designers” by Business Week in 2010 (BusinessWeek Names Don Norman One of World&amp;rsquo;s Most Influential Designers, 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In “Things That Make Us Smart,” Don Norman questions the interactions between humans and the technology that we create. Humans have always created tools to help extend our cognitive abilities, but modern technology is rapidly changing, and these changes have created a different relationship to humanity&amp;rsquo;s creations. To put the reader in the correct state of mind, the book begins with a quote from the 1933 Chicago Words Fair, “Science Finds, Industry Applies, Man Conforms.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the introductory chapters, we are reminded that humans have achieved our status in the animal kingdom due to our ability to build increasingly useful tools that extend our capabilities(Norman, 1994). We can extend our capabilities via the creation of cognitive artifacts. The most universal method to demonstrate this concept is pen and paper. This simple combination of tools has been shown to improve our ability to remember various text patterns, suggesting through external research that motor actions affect our ability to learn (Longcamp, 2006).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This text focuses on two specific modes of cognition, experiential cognition, and reflective cognition. Per the text, experiential cognition focuses on our perception of the objective world around us and how we react to external stimuli. Alternatively, reflective cognition is focused on more subjective ideas such as decision-making and thought processes. Reflective cognition the author describes is where growth occurs, and this is where the premise of the book begins to come into focus. When examining modern technology through this lens forces us to ask, are our interactions driving technology forward? Or are they allowing us to confuse experience for reflection?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reviewer of this book works in the cybersecurity industry and this question of user interaction has shown to have an elusive answer. As the use of technology increases, the risk to individuals also increases across areas such as privacy, data, or financial information. Yet, users continue to feel a “decreased motivation” to implement security controls in a manner not optimized around the way users process information (Adams &amp;amp; Sasse, 1999). This is in part because of a general distrust of the user by organizations. In 2014 SANS published a study that showed 51% of the surveyed companies felt that insiders were the primary threat, but only 28% of companies had a plan to monitor their users (Filkins, 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability of the text to generate reflective thoughts is one of the strengths of the book. Throughout its many chapters, Don Norman provides a framework to allow technical and non-technical readers the ability to explore their environment and identify areas that can improve from a shift in usability focus. Since it was originally published in 1994, this book has somehow kept up with the rapid changes in technology that followed. However, its clear writing and timeless examples have ensured that its guidance applies just as much today as when it was written.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
